A Guide to the Jordan Family Collection, 1752-1992 (bulk 1830-1930)
Library of Virginia
- Series II. Accounts and Receipts, 1829-1941., Extent: 10 boxes. (Box 29-38)
  Also in this series are receipts for saddle and harness supplies, pads, bits, rings, skirting, leather, rivets, collars, animal hair, pads and lining. There are some copies of Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company customer invoices.
  Arranged chronologically by year. Some years are also organized by first letter of customer or company name. Those particular records are mainly satisfied promissory notes and accounts of Jordan and Jordan.
  - 1829. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - 1830. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - 1831. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - 1832. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - 1833. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - 1834. (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - 1835. (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - 1836. (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - 1837. (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - 1838. (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - 1839. (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - 1840. (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - 1841. (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - 1842. (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - 1843. (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - 1844. (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - 1845. (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - 1846. (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - 1847. (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - 1847-1848. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - 1848. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - 1849. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - 1849 (A-D). (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - 1849 (E-H). (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - 1849.(J-M). (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - 1849 (N-R). (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - 1849 (S-V). (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - 1849 (W-Z). (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - 1850. (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - 1850 (A-D). (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - 1850 (E-H). (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - 1850 (J-M). (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - 1850 (N-R). (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - 1850 (S-V). (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - 1850 (W-Z). (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - 1851. (Box 30, Folder 17-18)
  - 1851-1852. (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - 1851-1852 (A-D). (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - 1851-1852 (E-H). (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - 1851-1852 (J-R). (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - 1851-1852 (S-V). (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - 1851-1852 (W-Z). (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - 1852. (Box 31, Folder 1-2)
  - 1852-1853. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - 1852-1853 (A-D). (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - 1852-1853 (E-H). (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - 1852-1853 (J-M). (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - 1852-1853 (N-R). (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - 1852-1853 (S-V). (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - 1852-1853 (W-Z). (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - 1853. (Box 31, Folder 10-11)
  - 1853 (A-D). (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - 1853 (E-H). (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - 1853 (J-M). (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - 1853 (N-R). (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - 1853 (S-Z). (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - 1854. (Box 31, Folder 17-18)
  - 1855-1858 (A-D). (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - 1855-1858 (E-V). (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - 1855. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - 1856. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - 1857. (Box 32, Folder 3-6)
  - 1858. (Box 32, Folder 7-8)
  - 1859. (Box 32, Folder 9-10)
  - 1860. (Box 33, Folder 1-2)
  - 1861. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - 1862. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - 1863. (Box 33, Folder 5-6)
  - 1863-1864. (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - 1864. (Box 33, Folder 8-9)
  - 1865. (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - 1866. (Box 33, Folder 11-12)
  - 1867. (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - 1868. (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - 1869. (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - 1870. (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - 1871. (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - 1872. (Box 34, Folder 3-4)
  - 1873. (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - 1874. (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - 1875. (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - 1876. (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - 1877. (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - 1879. (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - 1880. (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - 1881. (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - 1882. (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - 1883. (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - 1884. (Box 34, Folder 15-16)
  - 1885. (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - 1887. (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - 1888. (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - 1889. (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - 1890. (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - 1891. (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - 1892. (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - 1893. (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - 1894. (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - 1895. (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - 1896. (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - 1897. (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - 1898. (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - 1899. (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - 1900. (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - 1901. (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - 1902. (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - 1903. (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - 1904. (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - 1891-1899 (A-Y). (Box 36, Folder 1-20)
  - 1905. (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - 1906. (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - 1907. (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - 1908. (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - 1909. (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - 1910. (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - 1911. (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - 1912. (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - 1913. (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - 1914. (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - 1915. (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - 1916. (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - 1917. (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - 1918. (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - 1919. (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - 1920-1929. (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - 1930-1941. (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1-4)
- Series III. Subject Files, 1781-1992., Extent: 16 boxes. (Box 39-54)
  The subject files relate to iron manufacturing, the Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company, the Jordan Manufacturing Company, and other activities. They contain information relating to the Jordan family's iron manufacturing businesses including inventories, improvements, and expenses at Bath Forge, Buena Vista Furnace, Grace Furnace, Gibraltar Forge, Jane Furnace, Lydia Furnace, and Victoria Furnace. There are records of Amherst Furnace, including accounts, receipts, letters, orders, costs, property, and inventories. There are accounts of sales by various iron consignment merchants, including substantial correspondence with Crenshaw and Company and Kent, Paine, and Company of Richmond. The subject files also include slave hire bonds and receipts, and bills of sale for slaves purchased by Jordan.
  There are several files of note relating to Samuel F. Jordan's iron manufacturing operations during the Civil War. These include conscript details of persons exempted from military duty and detailed to work at Buena Vista Furnace. There is information relating to the impressment of Jordan's iron, cattle, and crops. Also included is a good deal of correspondence with the Confederate States of America Nitre and Mining Bureau, detailing Jordan's contract with the Bureau to supply pig iron suitable for the manufacture of weapons, as well as nails supplied to the Bureau. There are also records of Jordan's dealings with the Old Dominion Iron and Nail Works Company in Richmond, and their contract for the sale of pig iron, as well as numerous accounts. Lastly, there are records relating to the destruction of Buena Vista Furnace by Union forces on 13 June 1864, including inventories and values of property destroyed or confiscated.
  Subject files relating to the Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company include assets and liabilities, inventories of equipment and supplies, lists of shareholders, minutes of directors and stockholders meetings, stock certificates and subscriptions, and Wilbourn patent transfer agreements.
  Other topics included in this series are agreements, bank accounts and protests, bills of lading and shipping receipts, information from various commission merchants, dealers of woodworking equipment, machinery, tanners, and leather companies, coal dealers, automobile companies, and grocers and general merchandise dealers.
  There are records relating to Samuel F. Jordan's contract work with the North River Navigation Company in 1851, and also his work in 1870 for the James River and Kanawha Company to repair and restore various North River canals and locks to their condition prior to the flood in September 1870.
  There are building specifications for various Jordan family homes, deeds, fee bills, orders for payments or goods, photographs (mostly unidentified), Buena Vista post office records, promissory notes, Bible records of the Smith Family of Rockingham and Rockbridge Counties, and North Carolina, suit papers, tax tickets and receipts, a copy of the will of Samuel F. Jordan (1872), and papers of the Waesche family, including correspondence, autograph books, accounts and receipts, and miscellaneous items.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Accounts of Sales, 1841-1884. (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Accounts of Sales - Lewis Webb and Company, 1831-1836. (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Adams Bros. and Paynes, 1882. (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Agreements, 1836-1915. (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Agreements - Jordan and Jordan, 1847-1852. (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Air-Friction Carburetor Company, 1913. (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Alleghany Ore and Iron Company, 1917-1918. (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - American Solid Leather Button Company, 1895. (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - American Wood Working Machinery Company, 1909-1910. (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Amherst Furnace - Accounts and Receipts, 1867. (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Amherst Furnace - Accounts and Receipts, 1868. (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Amherst Furnace - Accounts, 1872-1883. (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Amherst Furnace - Letters, Orders, etc., 1868. (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Amherst Furnace - Costs, Profits, etc., 1869. (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Amherst Furnace - Merchandise Inventory, 1883. (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Anderson and Youel - Accounts, 1838-1839. (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Anderson, William T., 1857-1860. (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Antrim and Lafferty - Accounts, 1867-1868. (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Application for Electric Service, 1937. (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Appold Brothers, 1903. (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - Appraisement of Negroes, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Archibald Wheel Company, 1909. (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - Assets and Liabilities, 1889-1904. (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - Atwater Kent Manufacturing Works, 1916-1919. (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - Autocar Company, 1914. (Box 39, Folder 25)
  - Bacon and Lewis - Accounts, 1855-1859. (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - Bank of Buena Vista - Report to Stockholders, 1898. (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - Bank of Lexington, 1882-1884. (Box 39, Folder 28)
  - Bank of Rockbridge. (Box 39, Folder 29)
  - Bank Protests, 1854-1874. (Box 39, Folder 30)
  - Baptist Church of Lexington - Subscription List, 1851. (Box 39, Folder 31)
  - Barksdale, Jonathan - Orders, 1840. (Box 39, Folder 32)
  - Bath Forge - Inventories, Expenses, etc., 1830-1833. (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Bath Iron Works Improvements, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Bensons' Patent Water Ram, 1846. (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Bentel and Margedant Company, 1909. (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Bills of Lading, 1839-1849. (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Bills of Lading, 1850-1889. (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Bills of Lading, 1890-1899. (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Bills of Lading, 1900-1909. (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Bills of Lading, 1910-1940. (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Bills of Sale, 1933, 1938. (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Bills Payable/Receivable, 1891-1894. (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Boilers, Heaters, Radiators. (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Bonds, 1855, 1886. (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Boyd, James M. - Receipts, 1846. (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - James Boyd and Company, 1862. (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Boyd, Edmond and Davenport - Receipts, 1842. (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Breeden, Fox and Company, 1853-1859. (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Broadsides. (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Buena Vista Cannery Labels. (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Buena Vista Farm and Furnace - Costs, Expenses, etc. (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - Buena Vista Furnace - Historical Notes. (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Buena Vista Furnace - Inventories, 1847-1848, 1852. (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - Buena Vista Garden Club, 1935-1941. (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - Buena Vista Lumber Corporation, 1931-1932. (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - Buena Vista Mansion House Construction, 1849. (Box 40, Folder 25)
  - Buena Vista Ore Bank, 1883. (Box 40, Folder 26)
  - Buena Vista Presbyterian Church Program, 1965. (Box 40, Folder 27)
  - Buena Vista - Prospectus, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 28)
  - Buena Vista Woman's Club Yearbook, 1941-1943. (Box 40, Folder 29)
  - Buffalo Glove and Whip Manufactory, 1898. (Box 40, Folder 30)
  - Building Specifications. (Box 40, Folder 31)
  - Campbell, S. P., 1868. (Box 40, Folder 32)
  - Canal Papers, 1852. (Box 40, Folder 33)
  - Casper Company, 1909. (Box 40, Folder 34)
  - Catlett, R. H., 1867. (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Cement Receipts, 1852. (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Church Bulletins, 1929-1992. (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - City Treasurer Election, 1899, 1944. (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Clippings. (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Coal Accounts, 1913-1918. (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Cohn, Joseph, 1883-1884. (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Compton and Taylor, 1842-1847. (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Confederate Currency. (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Conscript Details, 1863-1864. (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Corbin Cabinet Lock Company, 1920 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Coughlin and Davis, 1913-1914. (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Crawford and Finney, 1859. (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Crawford and Pole, 1842-1854. (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Lewis D. Crenshaw and Company, 1845-1848. (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Lewis D. Crenshaw and Company, 1849-1850. (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Lewis D. Crenshaw and Company, 1851-1852. (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - Lewis D. Crenshaw and Company, 1853. (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Lewis D. Crenshaw and Company, 1854. (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Lewis D. Crenshaw and Company, 1855-1857. (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Lewis D. Crenshaw and Company, 1858-1859. (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Lewis D. Crenshaw and Company, 1860-1861. (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Crop Lien, 1886. (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Crow Motor Car Company, 1915. (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Damages by Federal Troops, 1864. (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Davidson, J. and G. K. - Accounts, 1867-1868. (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - George D. Davis Sons, 1883. (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Davis, William W., 1853-1855. (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - W. W. Davis and Company, 1863. (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Deeds, 1879-1948. (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Diamond Chain and Manufacturing Company, 1909. (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Dickenson, Willis E. - Orders, 1842. (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - W. S. and G. Donnan. (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Douthat, E. F., 1901. (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Echols, E. - Shipment Receipts, 1851-1853. (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Echols, Edward - Accounts, 1853-1854. (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Eidson, S. H., 1907-1908. (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Estate of John W. Hamilton. (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Estate of Charles F. Jordan. (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Estate of Col. John Jordan. (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Estate of Samuel F. Jordan. (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Estate of Virginia Jordan Rose. (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Estimated Cost of Wilbourn Saddle, 1889. (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Fairbanks Company, 1914. (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Faulkner and Craighill, 1883. (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - J. A. Fay and Egan Company, 1931. (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Fee Bills, 1835-1892. (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Figgat, Rutherford H., 1852-1869. (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Forest Service Rent Claim, 1934-1938. (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Gardner, Carlton and Company, 1858-1860. (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - A. L. Gebhardt and Company, 1913. (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Gibraltar Forge Inventory, 1843. (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - Gibraltar Forge and Jane Furnace Accounts, 1839-1845. (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - Gibson and Company, 1867-1870. (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - Gillock, Reuben L., 1849-1860. (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - Gordon, A., 1866-1867. (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Gourock Ropework Co. - Cotton Canvas Sample, 1899. (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Green Forest Iron and Steel Company, 1889. (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Grocery Bills, 1883. (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Guggenheimer and Company, 1883-1884. (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Hann-Brackenridge Company, 1910. (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Henderson, H. H., 1842-1864. (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Hermance Machine Company, 1909. (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Hill, Warren and Company - Answer to Bill, 1869. (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Hoffman, Thompson and Company, 1872. (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Hoffman, Thompson and Company, 1873. (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Hoffman, Thompson and Company, 1874. (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Hoffman, Thompson and Company, 1875. (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Hoffman, Thompson and Company, 1876-1877. (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Hoffman, Thompson and Company, 1878-1879. (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - R. C. Hoffman and Company, 1879-1880. (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - R. C. Hoffman and Company, 1881-1883. (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Hollins Institute, 1858-1871. (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Humphries, J. D., 1862-1867. (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - Hutton and Hall - Bills for Corn Meal Ground, 1842. (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - Hydraulic Water Ram Instructions. (Box 44, Folder 21)
  - Impressments of Cattle and Hay, 1863-1864. (Box 44, Folder 22)
  - Inventories of Equipment and Supplies. (Box 44, Folder 23)
  - Invitations and Announcements. (Box 44, Folder 24)
  - Iron Impressment, 1862. (Box 44, Folder 25)
  - James River Cement Works - Receipts, 1853. (Box 44, Folder 26)
  - Jane Furnace - Metal Receipts, 1843-1846. (Box 44, Folder 27)
  - Jenkins Bros., 1918. (Box 44, Folder 28)
  - Johnson Company, 1910. (Box 44, Folder 29)
  - Jones, Watts Brothers, and Co., 1883. (Box 44, Folder 30)
  - Jordan, B. J. - Orders, 1856. (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - B. J. Jordan and Co. vs. Samuel F. Jordan. (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Jordan, Col John - Accounts with S. F. Jordan, 1834-1856. (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Jordan and Davis - Accounts and Settlement, 1831-1850 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Jordan and Jordan - Accounts with S. F. Jordan, 1847-1856. (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Jordan Furnace Precinct Boundaries. (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Jordan, George W. - Settlement Papers (Various Estates), 1853-1868. (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Jordan, W. H. - Memoranda, Writings, etc. (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Kelly, John W., 1856-1871. (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Kent, Paine and Company, 1851-1859. (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Kerr, John, 1838-1843. (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Keys Piston Ring Company, 1916. (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Lease, 1904. (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Lee, Robert E. - Letter, 1869. (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Leyburn, E. J., 1867. (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - List of Machinery in Factory, 1904. (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Lists of Shareholders - Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company. (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Little, David - Orders, 1830-1831. (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - Locker, Henry S., 1853-1856. (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - Logan, John A., 1867-1868. (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - Lousiana Lottery Company, 1893-1894. (Box 45, Folder 21)
  - Lydia Furnace - Inventory of Property, 1837. (Box 45, Folder 22)
  - Mackey, Henry - Whisky Orders, 1855-1865. (Box 45, Folder 23)
  - Map - Allegheny and Pittsburgh, 1886. (Box 45, Folder 24)
  - Mapp, J. H., 1896-1920. (Box 45, Folder 25)
  - Martin, Charles, 1851-1854. (Box 45, Folder 26)
  - Mason, Nellie, 1895. (Box 45, Folder 27)
  - Massachusetts Investors Growth Stock Fund, 1963. (Box 45, Folder 28)
  - McCorkle and McDaniel, 1837-1841. (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - McCorkle and Simpson, 1848. (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - McCorkle, William, 1848-1851. (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - McCreath, Andrew S., 1883-1885. (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - McDaniel and Lee - Pig Iron Receipts, 1847. (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Medical Thesis (George D. Meriwether) (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Memoranda. (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Memorandum Book - Jane Furnace, 1839-1843. (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Merchandise Inventory, 1880. (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Merchants' Application for a State License, 1915-1916. (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Meriwether, George D., 1871-1884. (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Metal Made at Buena Vista Furnace, 1848-1852. (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Metal Production Form, 1915. (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Military Duty Exemptions, 1863. (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Milk Samples, 1918. (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Minutes - Buena Vista Saddle and Harness Company, 1889-1904. (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 46, Folder 17-21)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Montgomery Ward. (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Frank Massberg Company, 1914. (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Mt. Neriah Church School Society Constitution (portion) (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Muster Fines, 1829-1861. (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - National Hoist and Machine Company, 1905. (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Negro Hiring Expenses, 1854. (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Nesbitt, John - Orders from Bath Iron Works, 1830-1832. (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - New York Central Iron Works, 1918. (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Newhall, M. C., 1853-1857. (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Newham, James E., 1845-1856. (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Nitre and Mining Bureau - Correspondence, 1862-1864. (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - North River Canal Repairs, 1871. (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - North River Improvement Contract, 1870. (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - North River Improvements, 1851. (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - Newlin Bros. and Bigbie, 1880-1881. (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - Oath of Allegiance, 1865. (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - Obituaries. (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - Old Dominion Iron and Nail Works, 1862-1869. (Box 47, Folder 19)
  - Orders for Payment or Goods, 1830-1839. (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - Orders for Payment or Goods, 1840-1849. (Box 47, Folder 21)
  - Orders for Payment or Goods, 1850-1852. (Box 47, Folder 22)
  - Orders for Payment or Goods, 1853-1856. (Box 47, Folder 23)
  - Orders for Payment or Goods, 1857-1859. (Box 47, Folder 24)
  - Orders for Payment or Goods, 1860-1862. (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Orders for Payment or Goods, 1863-1864. (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Orders for Payment or Goods, 1865-1866. (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Orders for Payment or Goods, 1867-1869. (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Orders for Payment or Goods, 1870-1932. (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Orders for Payment or Goods, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Ordinance - Operation of Billiard and Pool Room, 1909. (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Ore Bank - Bills and Receipts, 1855-1856, 1865-1867. (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - C. S. Osborne and Co., 1900. (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - H. F. Osborne Co., 1894. (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Paine, Robert, 1858. (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Patent, 1905-1906. (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Paxton, J. H., 1868-1869. (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Pearl, Michael - Orders, 1856-1857. (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - B. Peyton - Sales of Pig Iron, 1836. (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Phillips, Martin, 1855-1857. (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Photographs. (Box 48, Folder 17-18)
  - Pig Iron Receipts, 1863-1866. (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Pig Iron Shipments, 1853-1861. (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Poetry. (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Robert Portner Brewing Company, 1913. (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Post Office, 1915-1927. (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Post Office - Buena Vista Furnace, 1864. (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Post Office - Discharge of Mabelle Jordan, 1922. (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Powers of Attorney. (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Promissory Notes, 1831-1849. (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Promissory Notes, 1850-1855. (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Promissory Notes, 1856-1859. (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Promissory Notes, 1860-1915. (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Proposal for Woodworking Machines, 1910. (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Protection Papers, 1862-1865. (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Proxies, 1869, 1895-1941. (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Pryibil, Paul, 1912. (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Railroad Freight Rates, 1883-1884. (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Ramsey, John B., 1936. (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Recipes. (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - "Reindeer" (Boat) - Receipts, 1872. (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - J. B. Renwick and Co., 1850-1852. (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Reports to Stockholders - Buena Vista Company, 1891, 1893. (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Resolutions - Neriah Church, 1860. (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Resolutions of Respect - Levi Truslow, 1923. (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - "Rip Van Winkle" - Piedmont Cigarette Series. (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Road Orders and Papers. (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Rockbridge Baths - Inventory, 1861. (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Rockbridge Historical Society - Proceedings, 1949. (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Saddle Orders. (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Saddle Orders, 1905-1906. (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - Sales Figures, 1899-1901. (Box 50, Folder 17)
  - O. M. Savels and Co., 1907. (Box 50, Folder 18)
  - Schewel Furniture Company - Rent, 1929-1935. (Box 50, Folder 19)
  - Samuel J. Shimer and Sons, 1914. (Box 50, Folder 20)
  - Sidney Steel Scraper Company, 1909. (Box 50, Folder 21)
  - Sidney Tool Company, 1909. (Box 50, Folder 22)
  - Silling, J. W., 1917-1920. (Box 50, Folder 23)
  - Slave Bills of Sale, 1839-1863. (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Slave Hire Bonds, 1840-1849. (Box 51, Folder 2)